Lazybones.
大懶蟲
Get up. Hurry.
起床了 快
I need to get some more sleep.
我再睡會兒
Captain Lu's men are here.
路隊的人來了
I haven't changed my clothes yet.
我還沒換衣服呢
Look how nervous you are.
瞧把你緊張的
They're outside.
門外呢
Isn't the flight tomorrow?
不是明天的飛機嗎
I just
我昨兒
called him yesterday.
剛給他打的電話呀
Hello, Aunt Gui Xiao.
歸曉阿姨好
Are you here alone?
自己來的嗎
Uncle Lu is downstairs.
路叔叔在樓下呢
Last night, Aunt Cai said
昨天晚上蔡阿姨說
she would take the train
她今天坐火車
to go abroad for business today.
出國做生意了
My dad said he was off today.
我爸說他今天正好休息
So he could send Aunt Cai off.
送蔡阿姨他們出關
Yes, I did mention it.
對 我說的我說的
Thank you so much.
謝謝你們
You're welcome.
沒事
Good morning.
早上好啊
Morning, Captain Lu.
早 路隊
Aunt Gui Xiao.
歸曉阿姨
Son.
兒子
What time did you sleep last night?
昨天幾點睡的
I didn't sleep.
沒睡
When we are on duty,
出任務的時候
it's normal not to sleep for a few days.
幾天不著床很正常
I'm used to it already.
習慣了
It's not easy for the country to train you guys.
國家培養你們不容易
You should take care of your health.
愛惜身體
So that you can work for a few more years.
這樣才能多幹幾年
It's the border.
邊境線
Is the photo you sent to me
當初你給我寄過的照片
taken here?
是這兒嗎
No.
不是
Later on,
以後
if you come to Qining again,
你有機會再來齊寧
I'll ask them to take you
我讓他們帶你去看
to the place where the photo was taken.
看照片的地方
I don't know
下一次
when will be the next time.
也不知道是什麼時候了
The view here is nice.
這裡風景不錯
You should look more at
祖國的大好河山
the beautiful rivers and mountains of our motherland.
該多看看
You've lived here for more than ten years.
你在這兒住了十幾年
I suppose
應該
it feels like looking at your hometown.
和看故鄉的感覺一樣吧
Captain Qin said
秦隊說
he would help me watch over my car for a week
幫我看一個星期的車
until I returned.
等我回來
It's very nice of him.
好人啊
Captain Qin, thanks.
秦隊 謝了
Don't mention it. We're friends.
客氣了 都是朋友
Thank you.
謝謝
You may go through the customs and take the train from there.
從那裡出去海關坐火車
Captain Lu,
路隊
once again, I would like to express
再次向您表達
my sincere gratitude to you.
誠摯的感謝
I'll treat you to a meal when I get back to Beijing.
等回了北京請您吃飯
Captain Lu, see you again.
路隊 有緣再見了
Bye.
再見
Okay, you can go now.
行 那你們走吧
Take care.
路上注意安全啊
Have a safe trip.
一路平安
Okay.
好
Bye.
再見
Aunt.
阿姨
Why don't you
你為什麼
go abroad with them?
不和他們一起出境
I have work to do in Beijing.
阿姨在北京還有工作
I need to go back to Beijing.
要回北京
The three of them came to Qining
他們三個來齊寧
for foreign trade.
是為了外貿生意
Aunt, why are you here?
阿姨 你來為什麼
Are you coming specially for Uncle Lu?
難道專程為了路叔叔
No.
不是
How could it be?
怎麼會
Xiaonan, if you keep talking nonsense,
小楠 老再瞎說的話
Aunt won't take you with her anymore.
阿姨不帶你走了啊
Lu.
老路
I've got an emergency mission.
緊急任務
I'll leave them to you.
他倆交給你了
Go ahead.
去吧
Xiaonan, be obedient to Aunt.
小楠 聽阿姨話
Thank you.
謝謝
Aunt, are you free after this?
阿姨 你一會兒沒事吧
Yes, I am.
沒事啊
Can you help me pack up my luggage?
那你能幫我收拾行李嗎
Why can't you do it yourself?
你為什麼不能自己收
What do you
有什麼東西
need help with from others?
是需要別人幫助的
None of us can.
我們都不行
Men are not careful enough.
男人心不細
We'll leave something out.
肯定會漏東西的
Okay.
好吧
Thank you.
謝謝
Does he live alone?
他平時自己住啊
When his dad comes,
他爸回來
he makes the bed up there
就把上面收拾一下
and sleeps on the upper bunk.
住上鋪
Why doesn't he apply for a dorm,
怎麼不申請宿舍呢
taking his son together?
帶著他一起
In our profession,
幹我們這一行的
once there is a mission,
要是真有任務時
our working hours will be uncertain.
工作時間不定
If the kid stays in the dorm,
怕孩子住宿舍
first, his resting will be disturbed.
一是被打擾作息
Second, seeing his dad often goes out,
二是看他爸經常出去
he'll be worried.
胡亂擔心
Kids nowadays are smart.
現在的孩子都聰明
He knows his dad's profession.
他知道他爸是幹嘛的
He'll be worried anyway.
那不照得擔心啊
Besides,
而且現在
there're numerous movies about explosive ordnance disposal nowadays.
很多的排爆電影
Doesn't he
他看了
ask you guys after watching them?
都不會好奇問你們嗎
Usually, we would say that
通常我們的回答都是
the movie scenes are all made-up.
電影裡都是瞎編的
It's not that dangerous.
沒那麼危險
So it's all true.
原來都是真的
It's dangerous, isn't it?
挺危險的是吧
Can't you even tell your friends?
朋友也不能說嗎
Every profession has difficulty.
一行有一行的不容易
There's nothing to say.
沒什麼可說
Is this all?
就這些
Doesn't his father
他爸
buy him clothes?
都不給他買衣服的嗎
Also, why doesn't
而且租房子
he rent
怎麼不租一個
a more spacious house?
大一點的呀
Isn't it too small
這爺倆住這兒
for them to live here?
會不會太小了
Are they your parents?
你爸媽呀
It's Uncle Lu and...
路叔叔和
Maybe
大概也許可能
his alumnus.
是他的校友
Why can't I understand
你這小孩說話
what you said?
我怎麼沒聽懂呢
Captain Lu is here.
路隊來了
I have to say hello to him.
我打聲招呼
They're developing feelings for each other.
人家培養感情呢
Are they helping you pack
他們在幫你收拾行李
and move?
幫你搬家
Thank you
這些年
for taking care of me all this time.
謝謝房東叔叔照顧
Why did you close the door?
關門幹嘛呀
The kid outside will get it wrong.
外邊孩子看了誤會了
We can talk conveniently if the door is closed.
關門好說話
His parents are divorced.
他父母離婚了
Qin Mingyu got his son.
秦明宇爭取到兒子
But deep down,
但是他內心覺得
he felt that he had dragged on Xiaonan's mother,
耽擱了小楠的媽媽
so he paid her a lot of money.
給對方補了不少錢
I see.
這樣啊
Now he has to take care of his parents
他現在養父母
and raise his son.
還要養兒子
So he doesn't dare to spend money freely.
不敢亂花錢
I've done packing the clothes.
衣服我收拾好了
I'll leave the books for you to pack since you're more familiar with them.
書你熟悉你收拾吧
I'll go out first.
我先出去了
My dad said...
我爸說
My dad said that
我爸說他 他今天晚上
he was not coming back for dinner tonight.
不回來吃飯了
I got it.
知道了
Let me see.
讓我看看
It's okay.
沒事 沒事 沒事
I'll go out first.
我先出去了
Otherwise, the kid will misunderstand.
不然孩子誤會了
Get out.
出去
This is even more misunderstanding.
這樣更誤會了
Remember to take
記得帶上
Qin Xiaonan's household registration permit
秦小楠的戶口本
for boarding purposes.
登機用
Stay in the car.
在車上待著
I need to talk to your aunt.
我跟阿姨有話說
He doesn't have a household registration permit.
他沒有戶口本
He doesn't?
沒有
His household registration permit
他的戶口
has been with his mother.
一直在他媽那兒
After the divorce,
離婚後
his mother always hopes
他媽一直希望
Xiaonan can live with her.
小楠過去跟她
Although the court has made a judgment,
雖然法院判了
these two
但這兩人
have been dilly-dallying regarding household registration.
過戶一直拖拖拉拉的
Qin Mingyu is also busy
秦明宇也忙
that he has no time to do it.
一直沒有時間去辦
Then, what should we do?
那怎麼辦啊
Does he have a passport?
有護照嗎
Yes.
辦過
Give me his passport first.
那先把護照給我
We'll discuss it after flying to Beijing.
先飛北京再說
But we need
但是上學
both the original and photocopy
需要戶口的原件
of his household registration permit.
和複印件
The school will need to verify them.
學校需要看
We'll figure this out this month.
這個月再想想辦法
Poor kid.
這小孩挺可憐的
Passport.
護照
I'll go back to Beijing after the Chinese New Year.
過年後我回北京
It's almost time.
差不多了
You may go in.
進去吧
Goodbye, Uncle Lu.
路叔叔再見
Alright.
行了
It's not like we'll never see each other again.
又不是不見了
We'll get going then.
那我們先走了
Why didn't your dad come to see you off?
你爸為什麼沒來送你啊
He hasn't been home for two days.
他這兩天都沒回家
He only called once.
就打過一個電話
It's okay.
沒關係
You can visit him during the summer break.
等寒暑假回去看他
I may not able to see him
回去了
even if I go back.
都不一定能見得到
Last year when I just arrived at Qining,
去年我剛到齊寧
my dad was on a mission,
我爸出任務
a confidential one.
保密的
I couldn't see him for days.
好幾天都沒見到人
Then,
那
what about you?
你怎麼辦呀
Was there no one who took care of you?
沒有人照顧啊
Yes.
有啊
The family of other team members took turns taking care of me.
隊裡的家屬輪流照顧我
But I cried every night.
就是我每天晚上老哭
I thought my dad had abandoned me.
以為我爸不要我了
Let me tell you.
我跟你說啊
I even cried
歸曉阿姨在高中的時候
when I was in high school.
還哭鼻子呢
My parents were divorcing at that time.
那會兒我爸媽離婚
So I cried a lot.
經常哭
You are so melodramatic.
那你可真矯情
What's wrong with you?
你這人怎麼這樣啊
I was trying to comfort you.
我好心安慰你呢
My dad said that I couldn't lie,
我爸說不能撒謊
especially to you.
尤其是對你
So I was being honest with you.
所以我就實話實說了
I won't argue with you.
不跟你計較
I'll take you hanging out tomorrow.
明天帶你出去玩啊
Where do you want to go?
想去哪裡
The Palace Museum, the Temple of Heaven
故宮 天壇
or the Great Wall?
還是長城
How about this?
這樣吧
I'll take you
我帶你
to visit
先把知名的景點
all the famous tourist spots
都逛個遍
before we go to the local spots.
再帶你一點點摸小地方
I don't want to go anywhere.
哪兒都不想去
We don't spend your dad's money.
不花你爸的錢
Your money is also money.
你的錢也是錢呀
That's Xinhe Hospital.
那是欣和醫院
Do you know it?
你知道啊
I know.
我知道
I used to go there when I was young.
我小時候經常去那兒
And there's also a 341 Hospital.
還有一個三四一
Is it nearby?
是不是在附近
I know it too.
我也知道
You know a lot.
你知道得挺多呀
Uncle Lu told me.
路叔叔跟我說的
He said
他說
he went to 341 Hospital
他去三四一
to visit a friend.
看過一個朋友
A hospitalized friend.
住院的朋友
Is it you?
是你
Maybe.
可能是吧
What do you mean by maybe?
什麼叫可能是吧
I can't remember.
我記不清了
We are arriving at my home.
我家快到嘍
That is the place you are going to stay
那就是你未來一個月
for the next month.
要住的地方
Come in.
進
This is the house I rent.
這是我租的房子
You can look around later.
一會兒你慢慢看
Come and change your shoes.
過來換鞋
Put them on.
穿吧 穿這雙
I can't help you manage the suitcase today.
我今兒弄不動箱子了
Take out your pyjamas.
你拿一件睡衣出來
I'll take you upstairs to take a shower and go to bed.
我帶你上樓洗澡睡覺
I usually
我平常
sleep naked.
光著睡
You have to wear clothes here.
在這兒你得穿衣服
I'm a girl.
我是女生
We should respect each other.
咱們要相互尊重
Okay.
好吧
I'm not familiar with this place.
我對這裡不熟
Can you buy it for me tomorrow?
明天你幫我買
Okay, leave it to me.
行 交給我
Thanks.
謝了
You finally came back.
終於捨得回來了
Didn't you be tied
沒被祖國大好河山
by the beautiful mountains and rivers of our motherland?
給拴住
Did anything happen
年前我們公司
before the Chinese New Year?
沒什麼大事吧
No.
沒有
It's almost New Year. Everyone is lazy.
快過年了 大家都懶
That's good.
那就行
By the way,
對了
there's a kid at my house.
我們家現在有個小孩
He's the child of my friend.
是朋友的孩子過來了
So I won't work overtime.
所以我就不加班了
If there are any needs,
有什麼工作呢
I'll work from home.
我就帶回去做
I'm fine with it.
我沒問題啊
I'm not the boss.
我又不是老闆
The boss is coming.
說誰誰就來啊
You're back.
回來了
Tomorrow is Laba.
明天臘八
I was worried
之前還擔心你
you wouldn't be able to catch up with the congee from Yonghe Palace.
趕不上雍和宮的祈年粥
Perfect.
剛好
Oh yeah.
對哦
I almost forgot.
你不說 我都忘了
Are we going together tomorrow
那明天我們一起去
or I queue up for you first?
還是我先幫你去排隊
No need.
不用不用
I'll take someone there.
我帶一個人去
Her friend's kid
她朋友家的小孩
will stay at her house until the Chinese New Year.
過年前寄住他們家
Okay.
行
Qin Xiaonan.
秦小楠
-Qin... -Coming.
秦 來了
Slow down. Be careful not to fall.
你慢點 別摔著啊
You've underestimated me.
你太小看我了
These stairs
就這些樓梯
won't hurt me.
摔不著我的
Why didn't you turn on the lights?
你幹嘛不開燈啊
It was dark when I came in.
我一進來黑不拉嘰的
You scared me.
嚇死了
I thought something happened to you.
我以為你出事了呢
It's on.
開著呢
I've turned on the desk lamp.
我開著檯燈呢
Your lights are too bright.
你這些燈太亮了
It must consume a lot of electricity.
一看就費電
I was not in the living room.
我不在客廳
so I switched off all of them.
所以就都給關了
Come here.
過來
Women like shopping.
女人就喜歡購物
These are all for you.
這都是給你買的
Heartless boy.
你個沒良心的
I don't have that much money for you.
我沒那麼多錢給你啊
They are at a 90% discount.
這些都是一折
All are on sale.
全部特價
I spent all the money
我把你給我的錢
you gave me to buy these.
我全花光了就買了這些
And I have points
而且我還有積分
to redeem the gifts for free.
可以免費換的
Points?
積分
You can redeem so many things?
能換這麼多東西
Of course.
能啊
I bought a lot in the past.
過去我買得多
So I got many points.
那積分當然就多了
You lied to me.
你騙我的
You money-grubber.
小財迷
You still have your wallet with you.
錢包還隨身帶著呢
What do you want for dinner?
晚上想吃什麼
I'll order takeout.
我點外賣
You are leaving one week earlier
比原定計劃
than planned.
提早一個星期走
Are you anxious to return home?
歸心似箭啊
Your son is in Beijing.
你兒子在北京
Aren't you worried?
你不擔心啊
He is with Gui Xiao.
有歸曉呢
It's better than with you.
比跟著你放心
Give this to Gui Xiao.
給歸曉
It's for Xiaonan's living expenses.
小楠的生活費
Where did you get the money?
哪兒來的錢
It's my bonus.
獎金
Gui Xiao bought not only clothes
人歸曉又給小楠
but also books for Xiaonan.
買衣服又買書的
Right? She provides food and accommodation.
是吧 包吃包住
We can't pretend to be unaware of it.
咱不能當不知道啊
Also,
還有啊
most importantly,
最重要的是
she introduced me to a school.
人家給我介紹了學校
A school?
學校
This helped me a lot.
這幫了我一大忙
She has done me a huge favour.
這可是天大的人情
Favour is the most valuable, do you know that?
人情最值錢了知不知道
Take it.
拿著
I will pay her.
我會給
You should keep your bonus to celebrate the New Year with your family.
獎金留給家裡過年用
What do you mean
我兒子你給錢
by paying for my son?
算怎麼回事啊
It's on your account.
先記賬
When you become rich,
等你以後發達
pay me triple.
三倍還
Okay.
行
Captain Lu.
路隊
I might come back in the future.
說不定還回來呢
You'd better not come back.
你還是別回來了
It's not easy for you to transfer back there.
這好不容易轉回去了
You should make up with
你趕緊把前嫂子
our ex-sister-in-law.
追回來吧
You're over 30 years old
都三十多歲的人了
but you still care about your pride.
還那麼要面子
If you like her, just go for it.
你喜歡就喜歡唄
Shut up.
閉嘴
I'm leaving.
走了
Take a leave as soon as possible
趕緊請假
and get the household registration permit back.
把戶口本拿回來
I remember that.
記著呢
You're finally back.
你總算回來了
Why didn't you inform me?
你怎麼不告訴我
I would pick you up.
我去接你啊
Let me see.
我看看
The campus beau in those days
當年的校草
is still so handsome.
還是那麼帥啊
Screw you!
去你的
Let's go.
走走走
Go home.
回家
I've booked
我晚上給你定了
the fanciest restaurant next to our house
咱們家旁邊最大的飯店
to welcome you.
給你接風洗塵
I don't have time to eat with you.
我來不及和你吃飯了
My mum is sick.
我媽生病了
I came back
我回來
to pack a change of clothes
拿幾件換洗的衣服
before I go to the hospital.
就得去醫院
Your mum is sick?
阿 阿姨病了
It's my fault.
這是我不好
I've been doing business
我前段時間
outside.
一直跟外頭跑生意
So I haven't had a chance to visit your mum.
沒去你家看咱媽 我
Meng Xiaoshan.
孟小杉
Cancel the table
我晚上訂那桌
I reserved for tonight.
你給我取消吧
I'm not going.
我有事不去了
My younger brother
我弟在我這兒
is dealing with the school application for Xiaonan.
給小楠辦學校
Have you got his household registration permit
你戶口本和出生證明
and birth certificate?
拿到沒有
Don't worry.
你放心吧
I'll be there next time.
改天我一定過去
I haven't got them yet.
我還沒拿到
Sorry, I'll be quick.
抱歉 我儘快
Not yet.
還沒有
Let's make up for it later.
那後補吧
Since it's confirmed,
反正定下來了
I'll hold off for you with my guarantee.
我拿臉面先給你拖著嘍
Thanks.
謝了
What's wrong with you?
你怎麼回事
How many donations
姐當初
has Sister made for us
幫我們拉了多少善款
for the mountainous area?
去山區
Without her,
要是沒有姐
would you have connected with so many prestigious schools?
你能認識這麼多好學校
Guarantee?
還臉面
Your guarantee is valid because of Sister.
臉面不都是姐給你的
Yes.
是
Don't bother him, Sister.
別理他 姐
Well,
那個
as for the procedures afterwards,
後續還需要辦什麼手續
make a list for me.
你就列個單子給我
I'll finish them during the winter break.
我趁寒假辦了
I'll give it to you tomorrow.
明天給你
Okay.
好
I'll get it for you, Uncle.
我去倒吧 叔叔
Good boy.
真乖
You've been to the north
你說你去北邊散心
for less than a week,
沒一個星期
but you took back
就帶回來個
a kid you didn't know before.
沒見過面的小孩
Not only are you
給人解決
helping with his education,
讀書問題不說
but you also filled in his regular address as your home.
常住地址都填的自己家
Sister, if you weren't a woman
姐 要不是你是個女的
and couldn't satisfy the condition,
咱基本能力沒法滿足
I would have thought that
我真以為這小孩
he was
是你留在外面的
your illegitimate child.
私生子呢
You're right.
你別說還真像
Right?
是吧
Let's have dinner together tonight.
晚上一起吃飯吧
I'll book a restaurant.
我訂個餐廳
Don't bother, Sister. You're always so generous.
別了姐 老讓你破費
Can't I take the kid
我想帶小孩開個葷
to have some meat?
不行啊
Go. Put on your down jacket.
去 把羽絨服拿下來
The one I bought for you.
我給你買的那件
How about this?
那這樣吧
We'll go downstairs and wait in the car.
我們先下樓開車
Okay, see you downstairs.
好 樓下見
Take it.
拿著
Okay, let's go.
好 走
Here's your bill.
單子拿好
Okay.
好
Do you have enough money? I have some with me.
夠不夠 我這兒帶著呢
Yes.
夠
It's settled.
妥了
It's not like you to smile at your phone.
對著手機笑不像你啊
Is it a beauty from Qining?
齊寧的美女
Watch over my mum.
幫我看著我媽
I'll pay the bill.
我去繳費
My dad said
我爸說
Uncle Lu always risked his life on missions.
路叔叔出任務可拼命了
He led the team to arrest the culprits
帶隊抓人
for two days and two nights.
抓了兩天兩夜
After crossing five snow-capped mountains,
翻了五座雪山
the claws of police dogs covered with blood,
警犬的爪子上都是血
he was still chasing after them.
還在追
In the end, he caught them.
後來追到了
Nobody can get away
沒有路叔叔
from Uncle Lu.
抓不回來的人
Once, they went on a mission
還有一回他們出任務
at a forbidden zone of life
去海拔五千多米的
with an elevation of about 5,000 metres.
生命禁區
They'd walked a dozen kilometres
徒步走了十幾公里
and carried out the villagers who passed out with oxygen deficiency.
往出背缺氧昏迷的老鄉
The villagers recovered after being carried out,
回來老鄉沒事
but some team members had altitude sickness
隊裡有人高原反應
and almost died.
差點就不行了
Aunt Gui Xiao.
歸曉阿姨
How did you
你們
know each other?
怎麼認識的
We're alumni.
校友
You're indeed alumni?
還真是校友
I thought it was an excuse.
我還以為是藉口呢
His name was Lu Chen at first.
他最開始叫路晨
Later, he changed his name by adding Yan in the middle.
後來改名字加了一個炎
Do you know that?
知道嗎
No wonder.
難怪呢
No wonder what?
難怪什麼
That day in the parking lot,
那天在停車場
you called him Lu Chen.
叫叔叔路晨
I felt weird at that time.
我還有點奇怪
Although we went to the same school,
我們雖然是同校
I hadn't met him
但是一開始
at first,
我也沒見過他
but always heard about
就老聽說
Lu Chen in the 12th grade
高三有個叫路晨的
having a good look.
長得特別帥
And then?
後來呢
That's our business. Kids can't inquire about it.
大人的事不許追問
Xiao.
曉曉
This is my cousin, Lu Chen.
這是我表哥 路晨
Lu Yanchen.
路炎晨
Yes, when he was in school,
對 後來上學的時候
he changed his name because it duplicated with others.
碰到重名就改了
But we still
不過家裡人
call him Lu Chen.
都還叫他路晨
Boss, two more.
老闆 再來兩串
Okay.
好嘞
Hi, Gui Xiao.
歸曉 來了
Have you done your summer homework?
你暑假作業寫完了嗎
Yet you're hanging out here.
就跑出來玩
Aren't you the same?
你不也是嗎
I'm going to celebrate Meng Xiaoshan and others' graduation.
慶祝孟小杉她們畢業嘛
It's an exceptional case.
特殊
Are you coming to celebrate Meng Xiaoshan's birthday,
給剛畢業那孟小杉
who has just graduated?
過生日的
Yes.
對
Turn right. The innermost one.
右拐 最裡邊那間
Thank you.
謝謝
What are you laughing at?
笑什麼
Believe it or not, I'll pocket all in the next round.
信不信下一杆我全收了
I don't think so.
我看懸
We have made a bet.
我們打賭呢
Whoever wins will buy the beverages.
誰贏了 誰請喝水
Won't he get a heat stroke
穿這麼多
wearing so much?
不會中暑嗎
Chen.
晨哥
Chen, this is Meng Xiaoshan's sister
這是孟小杉的妹妹
and my sister-in-law, Gui Xiao.
我小姨子 歸曉
Game.
收球
Let me play in the next game.
下一局我來
You're even shorter than the cue stick.
你這人還沒杆高呢
You'd better just watch them playing.
乖乖看著吧
Didn't you make a block booking?
你不是都包場了嗎
There are no outsiders here. I'm just playing for fun.
又沒外人 我打著玩
Yes.
對呀
You've booked for a whole afternoon anyway.
反正都包了一下午
Just let her play.
你就讓她玩唄
I'll go get some water.
我出去拿個水啊
Brother, where are you going?
哥 你去哪兒啊
I'll play with you for one game.
我陪你打一局
You've been sitting here all afternoon.
你這坐一下午了
You finally have the mood to exercise.
終於有心情活動活動了
I am no match for you.
我打不過你
I'll use my left hand.
我用左手
The rule is who clears the table first, who wins.
規則是誰先清檯誰贏
In this way, the chances of winning are high.
這麼一說倒是勝率很大
I'll start the move.
我開
Of course.
當然了
♫Hi, what day is today?♫
晨哥都讓你到這份上了
How can he not let you start the move?
還能不先讓你開球啊
No way, Chen.
不是 晨哥
♫Hi, what day is today?♫
別這麼欺負
Gui Xiao.
我們家歸曉啊
Yes.
是啊
♫Can I see you?♫
今天孟小杉過生日
Why are you bullying her sister?
你欺負人家妹妹算什麼
♫Let my heartbeat continue at 110 bpm♫
就是啊 晨哥
Give in to her.
讓一個呀
He's already using his left hand.
都左手了還讓
Why don't you ask Gui Xiao
你乾脆讓歸曉
to grab the balls and put them directly in the pockets?
直接拿手扔袋裡得了
Do you want me to take a dive?
想要我讓嗎
No.
不用
I'll go and buy something.
我去買點東西
It's hot.
燙死了
♫I'll sing for you♫
忘了停在陰涼處了
Did you burn your butt?
燙著屁股了
Chen.
晨哥
Chen, are you leaving?
晨哥走了
Later I found out
後來我才知道
something happened to Lu Chen's family
那年高考的前一天
one day before the Gaokao.
路晨家裡出大事了
He didn't settle it until the next afternoon
耗到第二天下午才解決
and missed
錯過了
the first exam in the morning.
上午的第一場考試
No one knew
沒有人知道
whether he was going to repeat his final year
他到底是復讀
or work at the repair factory of his family.
還是接家裡修理廠去了
Since then,
自那以後
I never saw him again.
我就再也沒有見過他了
Until...
直到
Sister-in-law, here.
小姨子 來
I'll treat you to pancakes.
哥請你吃煎餅
Take it easy.
悠著點
Here, the pancake is ready.
來 煎餅好了
Look how skinny my sister-in-law is.
看給我小姨子瘦得
Add two eggs for me. Pick the big ones.
倆蛋啊 挑大的來
Okay.
好嘞
Boss, a pancake, please.
老闆 來個煎餅
Okay, please wait a moment.
好嘞 請稍等
Come on, handsome, your pancakes.
來 帥哥 你煎餅
Here.
來 給
Thank you.
謝謝
You're welcome.
客氣什麼呀
My future bridesmaid.
我以後的伴娘
My bike.
車
My brother didn't take the Gaokao that day
我哥那天沒去高考
because he applied for the police academy
就是因為瞞著他爸
without telling his dad.
偷偷報了警校
His dad made a scene before the exam
在考前被大鬧了一場
and locked him up in the garage
關進車廠裡面
for two days and three nights.
整整兩天三夜
The first exam was finished by then.
第一科目都考完了
He was released in secret
才被我二姨
by my aunt after that.
偷偷放出來的
But it was too late.
可終究還是來不及了
Why?
為什麼呀
Even he applied for the police academy, so what?
警校怎麼了
My aunt had divorced my uncle before.
我二姨和我姨父離過婚
She married a cop after that.
二婚找了個警察
That cop was very nice.
那個警察可好了
He treated my cousins well.
對我表哥表姐都超級好
But later he got sick and died.
就是後來生病 走了
My aunt had no income.
我二姨又沒有收入
She couldn't afford to raise two children.
養不起兩個孩子
So she remarried my uncle.
就跟我姨父又復婚了
Probably because of jealousy.
估計是因為吃醋吧
I heard it from my mum.
我聽我媽說的啊
When my uncle
我姨父
knew my cousin had applied for the police academy,
知道表哥報了警校
he went crazy.
整個人都發瘋了
He must have recalled
應該是想起
my aunt's second marriage.
二姨改嫁的事了
You can never ask
這話千萬千萬
my cousin about this.
別問我表哥啊
We don't talk much.
我跟他都不怎麼說話的
Really?
是嗎
I thought you were close
我以為你倆挺熟的呢
because of Meng Xiaoshan.
因為孟小杉
Gui Xiao. I'll wait for you at the school gate.
歸曉 學校門口等你啊
It's my brother's birthday today.
今兒我哥過生日
Do I need to buy a gift?
那我需要買禮物嗎
Come on.
你可得了吧你
You bought plush toys
咱班哪個同學過生日
for every student in our class on their birthdays.
你都給人買毛絨玩具
You've almost
那精品屋
hollowed out the shop.
都快被你掏空了
Meng asked you to go empty-handed.
孟姐說了讓你空手去
Okay. Wait for me.
好 那你等我
I'll hand in the paper.
我去交卷子
He must be there on Haidong's birthday.
海東生日 他一定在
This is the factory of Chen's family.
這就是晨哥家廠子
But customers usually don't come here.
但客人一般不來這兒
They have to go to the storefront if they need the repairs.
送修得去門店
Chen.
晨哥
You're here.
來了
Sit here.
坐這兒
Gui Xiao.
歸曉
Let me introduce them.
我介紹一下啊
These are my old classmates.
這些呢都是我的老同學
This is Meng Xiaoshan's sister.
這個呢是孟小杉的妹妹
Her name is Gui Xiao.
叫歸曉
This is my younger brother, Hai Jianfeng.
這是我弟 海劍鋒
They are our own people.
都自己人
Lu Chen's room is too cold.
路晨這屋太冷了
Put it on.
你穿著吧
You guys are still in high school.
你們幾個還在上高中呢
You can't drink.
可不能喝酒啊
Don't worry. I won't let them drink.
放心吧 不讓他們喝
This should be where he lives.
這應該是他住的地方
Is this
這是不是
Hai Jianfeng's best friend?
海劍鋒好朋友啊
No, no.
不 不 不
No.
不是 不是
This is my sister.
這是我姐
He's no match for Gui Xiao.
這臭小子可比不上歸曉
I'm serious.
我說認真的
My sister not only has good grades
我這妹妹成績一流
but also is talented in sports
又是體特生
and is a member of the school choir.
和校合唱團的
She is definitely
絕對是
the favourite of all teachers.
各科老師的心頭肉
A straight-A student? Not bad.
學霸啊 可以啊
Are there enough dishes?
菜夠不夠
No.
不夠
I want to eat pickled cabbage with vinegar sauce.
這個醋溜白菜還想吃
One more.
再來一個
Coming.
來了
Good.
可以
Try it.
嚐嚐
Chen.
晨哥
Your cooking is so good.
你這手藝太可以了
Of course.
那當然了
You don't have to rush back, right?
不著急回去吧
It's my birthday today.
我今天過生日
We finally get together.
好不容易大家聚一次
Otherwise,
要不然
I don't dare to waste your study time.
不敢耽誤你學習的時間
No hurry.
不著急
It's Friday.
今天星期五
Okay, that's good.
行 那就好
Try it. Lu Chen is good at cooking.
嚐嚐 路晨手藝可好了